There are heroes. There are superheroes. And then there's Hancock.
Hancock is a fantasy, action film directed by Peter Berg.
Hancock is a down-and-out superhero who's forced to employ a PR expert to help repair his image when
the public grows weary of all the damage he's inflicted during his lifesaving heroics.
The agent's idea of imprisoning the antihero to make the world miss him proves successful, but
will Hancock stick to his new sense of purpose or slip back into old habits?
John Hancock, played by Will Smith.
Mary, played by Charlize Theron.
Ray, played by Jason Bateman.
Aaron, played by Jae Head.
Red, played by Eddie Marsan.
Man Mountain, played by David Mattey.
Hancock is a 2008 American superhero film starring Will Smith as John Hancock, an
amnesiac, alcoholic, reckless superhuman trying to remember his past.
The film is directed by Peter Berg and written by
Vince Gilligan and Vy Vincent Ngo.
The film also stars Charlize Theron, Jason Bateman and Eddie Marsan.
The story was originally written by Vy Vincent Ngo in 1996.
It languished in development hell for years with various directors attached, including Tony Scott, Michael Mann (who would later co-produce the
film), Jonathan Mostow and Gabriele Muccino, before being filmed in mid-2007 in Los Angeles with a production budget of $150 million.
In the United States, the film was rated PG-13 by the Motion Picture Association of America after changes
were made at their request in order to avoid an R rating, which it had received twice before.
Columbia Pictures released the film in theaters in
the United States on July 2, 2008.
While Hancock received mixed reviews from critics, who found it promising, but let down by the mid-movie change
in tone, it grossed $629.4 million worldwide, becoming the fourth highest-grossing film of 2008.
The film explores themes of love of one's life, flying,
alcohol, advertising expert, superhero.